Hello English learners. Welcome back to another podcast
here with us at English pod. My name is Marco and I'm Erica
and today we are going to be looking at a very useful
lesson because well sometimes you need to call a plumber.
Okay, so first of all why
don't we start with vocabulary
preview because I think we
need to know this word polymer.
Very vocabulary preview. Alright so
on vocabulary preview today we're going
to look at two words and the first one
is the one that we mentioned plumber.
A plumber. So it's a person A plumber. And
a plumber is the person who fixes everything
in your house that is related to water. Okay
so he fixes the toilet, the sink, the shower.
Yeah that's the plumber. And now
the second word is obviously related
to plumber and it's water pipes.
Water pipes. Water pipes. The pipes.
So the plumber fixes or
looks at the water pipes as well.
Yeah and those are a tube that
carries water in and out of your house.
Okay so water pipes. You also have different types of
pipes like gas pipes. Okay so what are we learning in
this lesson? So in this lesson we're going to be learning
how to describe when you have problems with plumbing.
When you have problems in your sink or in your toilet and
how you can describe it. And so I think we should take
a look at our dialogue for the first time and see what
types of problems this woman is having with her plumbing.
Good afternoon. Did you call for a plumber? Yes
yes I did. Please come in. I'm so glad you came.
This old house is falling apart. Come into the
bathroom. See here there's water leaking everywhere.
I see. Let me have a look. That
seems that your toilet is clogged
and that's why it won't flush.
Let me just get my plunger.
No that's not working either. I suspect
that there's some sort of foreign object
in the pipe that's causing a blockage.
That's what's making your toilet overflow.
Oh that must be because of my four-year-old daughter. She
has always questioned things down in toilet. You know how
kids are. Yeah I have a little one myself. Anyway these
water pipes are really rusty so they also should be changed.
That could be causing water to not drain completely.
That might lead to more problems in the future. I would
suggest fixing this faucet that isn't shutting off properly.
I could have it all finished by today if it's urgent.
That would be great.
Is it expensive? Let's see.
That would say about $800.
What? That's more than I make.
All right well it sounds like she's having
some big problems with her plumbing
but actually I'm really interested that
the plumber makes so much money.
That is a very interesting thing and we're going to
talk a little bit about that later on but I think
we should look at those kind of difficult words that
we found in the dialogue now in language takeaway.
So we have five words here all to
do with a plumber and water pipes.
Now the first word they talked about
that there was water leaking everywhere.
So you have water leaking. Water leaking. So to leak. When
something leaks it lets liquid come out when it shouldn't.
Okay when it shouldn't. So maybe you have a bottle of water
and it's closed but maybe there's a hole in the bottle.
So it leaks. So it leaks. All right and so
there was water everywhere it was leaking and
maybe the reason was because the toilet is
clogged. Okay clogged. The toilet's clogged.
Clogged. Now what does it mean if the toilet
is clogged? If the toilet is clogged there
is something that stops the water from going
down. Okay so there's something blocking it.
Okay a clogged toilet. Now the plumber said that it might be
clogged and he tried to fix it with a plunger. A plunger. A
plunger. Okay so it's kind of hard to describe what a plunger is
so why don't we listen to the sound a plunger makes in a toilet.
All right so the plunger is the tool that you use to
unclog a toilet. Okay that's what you use a plunger. So the
plunger didn't work and he wasn't able to fix the toilet and
he said there's something in the pipes causing a blockage.
All right so our next word a blockage. Blockage. Well a blockage is something that stops water
from flowing. Okay so something is blocking it. So you have blockage. Yep very good and we have
one more word on language takeaway and that word is faucet. A faucet. A faucet. All right so the
faucet is the part of the sink that lets water come out. Okay so you have a faucet in your sink.
Yeah so you put your hands under the faucet so you can wash them. Okay that's the faucet.
Yeah very good. So now that we've learned about these different tools and these different
ways of describing problems with your plumbing let's listen to this dialogue another time
a little bit slower now and then we'll come back and take a look at some great phrases.
Good afternoon. Did you call for a plumber? Yes yes
I did. Please come in. I'm so glad you came. This
old house is falling apart. Come on into the
bathroom. See here there's water leaking everywhere.
I see. Let me have a look. It seems
that your toilet is clogs and that's why
it won't flush. Let me just get my
plunger. No that's not working either.
I suspect that there's some
sort of foreign object in the pipes
that's causing a blockage. That's
what's making your toilet overflow.
Oh that must be because
of my four-year-old daughter.
She is always flushing things down
the toilet. You know how kids are.
Yeah I have a little one
myself. Anyway these water
pipes are really rusty so
they should also be changed.
That could be causing
water to not drain completely.
That might lead to more
problems in the future.
I would also suggest fixing this
faucet that isn't shutting off properly.
I could have it all finished
by today if it's urgent.
That would be great. Is it expensive?
Let's see. I would say about $800.
What? That's more than I make
in a day and I'm a hot surgeon.
We've got three phrases
that you can use when you
need to describe something
not working with the pipes.
So let's look at them now in
Fluency Builder. Fluency Builder.
So the lady called the plumber
and he arrived and well she
described her house as
old and that it's falling apart.
It's falling apart.
This old house is falling apart.
So when something is falling
apart it's old and it's breaking slowly.
Exactly. So we can
say the house is falling
apart or maybe this
old car is falling apart.
You can also use it for people.
Oh I'm getting so old and falling apart.
Very good. So you're getting sick or yeah.
Very good. Now for our second word.
Well the woman said that maybe her daughter
was flushing things down the toilet.
Okay so to flush something down the toilet.
To flush something down the toilet.
So before we explain this let's
listen to a toilet being flushed.
Okay so that's the sound
of flushing and when
you flush something down
the toilet what happens?
So basically you throw
something into the
toilet and then you
flush it so it goes away.
All right so flushing
something down the toilet.
Well she also talked about the faucet
and it wasn't shutting off properly.
Shutting off. To shut
off. Okay shut off.
When you shut something
off you turn it off.
Okay so we can say to shut
something off or to shut off something.
Right so hey Marco can
you shut off the computer?
Okay or I can say can
you shut the faucet off?
Exactly. Great so we
took a look at these three
phrases that will help
you describe again these
situations or problems
that may happen in your
bathroom or with liquids
and well let's listen to
the dialogue for the last time and
we'll come back and talk a little bit more.
Good afternoon did you call for a plumber?
Yes yes I did. Please come in.
I'm so glad you came this old house is
falling apart. Come into the bathroom.
See here there's water
leaking everywhere.
I see let me have a look
and it seems that your toilet
is clogged and that's why it won't flush.
Let me just get my plunger.
Well that's not working
either. I suspect that
there's some sort of
foreign object in the pipe
is causing a blockage.
That's what's making your
toilet overflow. Oh that
must be because of my
four-year-old daughter.
She has always questioned
things down in toilet.
You know how kids are?
Yeah I have a little one myself.
Anyway these water pipes are really
rusty so they also should be changed.
That could be
causing water to not
drain completely. That might
lead to more problems in the future.
I would suggest fixing this faucet
that isn't shutting off properly.
I could have it all finished
by today if it's urgent.
That would be
great. Is it expensive?
Let's see. I would say about $800. What?
That's more than I'm making a day.
Well we heard in this
dialogue that this plumber
is making about $800.
That's a lot of money.
That's a lot of money. And actually this in
many countries is not far from the truth.
That's right like for example
in Canada there is a shortage.
There's not enough of these
people like plumbers who can do this type
of work so they can charge a lot of money.
So this type of work is
called a he's not really
a professional right? Right, but he is a
trades person because he works in a trade.
Okay so like a plumber and an
electrician, a person that paints
your house, those
are all trades.
And well it is true because
now many people don't want to
learn or do these types
of trade because well
it's not considered to
be such a great job right?
Yeah but the funny
thing is now if you're a
plumber and you get
your first job as a you know
young person you can
make so much more money
than a person with a
history degree for example.
Exactly because there
is a shortage of these
types of what you can
call them professionals.
Yep right so well what
about in your countries let
us know how these types
of trades work, are there
many of them, are there
not many of them because
well of course in
different countries it's a
little bit different right
in some countries there
are too many tradesmen. So
visit us at our website EnglishPod.
com and tell us
all about that and
remember if you have any questions about
the lesson you can ask them there as well.
All right so we'll see you
guys there and until next time.
Thanks for downloading and good bye!